( PANTING )
( TRAIN PASSING )
Oh , fuck !
( CREAKING )
I wasn 't trying to escape .
( CRYING ) No , please . Don 't .
Oh , God . I don 't want to die .
Yeah . Yeah , I 'll make you clean .
I 'm sorry .
I didn 't mean to ...
( ALARM BEEPING )
( DOOR OPENING )
( SHOWER RUNNING )
Hey , sis .
What time is it ?
Just after 8 : 00 .
You want me to make coffee ?
No , I gotta go . I 'll call you later .
You sure there 's nothing I can do ?
Angie , everything 's gonna be fine . Just go back to sleep .
( DOORBELL BUZZING )
LORENZO ON INTERCOM : All right , I 'm coming , I 'm coming .
BEN : Ben Carson .
Lorenzo Sapelli . I 've been waiting for you . Come on in .
BEN : Thanks .
How long you been working here ?
LORENZO : All together ? Fifteen years .
BEN : You were here for the fire ?
LORENZO : Devastating .
Entire building up in flames .
( DOOR OPENING )
It has been five years since the fire .
They 're still in a legal battle with the insurance companies .
Even cleaning up this mess is impossible .
I 've given up faith about reopening , and besides ,
who 'd ever want to shop here after everything that 's happened ?
You know , the Meredith family acquired this building
after St. Matthew 's Hospital closed in 1952 .
It was the very first Mayflower to open on the East Coast .
Yeah , the company wants us to patrol the premises every couple of hours ,
but I do my rounds every three . That 's more than enough .
Anyway , you 'll see , not too much going on . It 's pretty calm around here .
Well , there you go .
Perfume and cosmetics department , what 's left of it anyway .
Thank God you didn 't show up any later . This place gives me the creeps at night .
No electricity .
All these mirrors .
- Best to keep your eyes away from them . - BEN : You polish them ?
- I 'm sorry ? - The mirrors , they 're so clean .
No , that 's Gary . Gary Lewis .
Fellow who was working here before you .
He was completely obsessed with these damn mirrors .
Spent the entire night cleaning them .
How long has it been since you left the NYPD ?
About a year .
I know it 's none of my business , but why did you resign from the force ?
You used to be a detective , is that correct ?
Yeah .
I 'm sorry .
( CHUCKLES ) I always been too curious .
It 's all right .
LORENZO : There was a pretty big team working here before the fire .
You know , when you stop to think , of all the department stores in New York ,
this one was the most beautiful , most luxurious .
I mean , it breaks your heart , it really does .
Well , here you go .
This is where you 'll be spending most of your time .
At least you got electricity in here .
It 's warm . It 's nice .
You 've even got a TV .
WOMAN ON TV : I opened up the trunk , which he so called hid the pictures .
I grabbed the goody bag , walked to the backyard ,
opened up the barbecue grill , I grabbed the lighter fluid ,
Waiting to Exhale .
Hello ?
ROSA : Hello .
- Hey , Rosa , how are you doing ? - I 'm fine . Let me help you .
Thanks .
Where are the kids ?
Upstairs with Señor Ben .
AMY : Thanks .
DAISY : So everybody at my school thinks this boy named Eamon ,
which is , like , one of my best friends , which is a boy , likes me .
And this girl named Christiana , who liked him , is just now gossiping .
BEN : You want me to talk to Mrs. Ward ?
She 'll make them want to wrap me up in toilet paper for Halloween .
- Hey . - AMY : Hey .
Look , Mommy . Look what Daddy got me .
It looks great . You 'll have to show me how it works later , okay ?
It 's so fast , Mommy .
Ben ? Can I talk to you ?
Yeah . Okay , you two .
You need to finish your homework . You need to get ready for your bath .
Come on . No fooling around , let 's go .
Okay , let 's go , Michael .
Hey . Come here .
Happy , happy birthday .
MICHAEL : Thanks , Dad . BEN : Yeah .
- Hey . - Hey .
( DOOR CLOSING )
- What is this ? - What ?
I 've asked you not to drop by without calling .
You won 't answer my calls .
( SCOFFS ) Please , Ben , I don 't want to argue with you .
I don 't want to argue , either . If you 're not gonna answer my calls , what ...
I haven 't had a drink for over three months ,
but since you won 't answer your calls , how would you know ?
I don 't want to know .
What I want is for you to respect my needs .
Amy , I 'm doing everything I can to respect your needs .
I haven 't had a drink .
I got a new job to hold me over till I 'm reinstated .
I 'm doing everything I can to get back on my feet again .
What ?
You don 't think people can change ?
We 're not talking about people . We 're talking about you .
Amy , I killed a man .
You don 't just get over that .
I needed time . I needed you .
- I was right here . - Yeah .
Judging me like everybody else .
How dare you say that to me ?
I was the only one at the precinct who defended you .
How many times did I chase reporters off our front lawn ?
How can you say that to me ?
I 've always been in your corner !
I 've been the only one who believed in you !
You 're fucking unbelievable !
Please , I didn 't come here to fight .
Look , I 'm sorry that I came over without calling .
I just wanted to see them .
But we have to set up some rules .
What fucking rules ?
Come on , Amy , just tell me what rules I need to follow
so I can see my son on his birthday !
Look at yourself .
This is exactly what I 'm talking about .
I don 't know how you 're going to be from one moment to the next .
When I get around you , I get nervous .
Because I am so scared that I am losing you .
And I screw everything up .
- I 've missed you so much . - I miss you , too .
Amy , we deserve another chance .
I know how much I love you , and I know somewhere inside there , you love me , too .
Please .
AMY : I can 't do this .
I can 't do this , Ben .
Fuck .
( DOOR OPENING )
( DOOR CLOSING )
( KETTLE WHISTLING )
( MAN CHATTERING ON TV )
( ALARM BEEPING )
( BIRDS FLUTTERING )
Holy shit .
( DOOR OPENING )
( DOOR CREAKING )
What the hell ?
Fuck !
Man .
What the ...
- You should stop taking those pills . - Jesus !
( SIGHS )
How are you doing today ?
I 'm fine . I feel a lot better . I 'm leaving in a couple of minutes .
Are you sure you 're all right ?
Please , not you .
Okay . I 'm just saying , you can talk to me if you want .
I 'm your little sister .
It 's that new job , isn 't it ?
Yeah , well , I need that new job .
I can 't take care of Amy and the kids and myself on my pension .
I 'm not gonna sleep on your couch for the rest of my life .
Okay , well , maybe you get a daytime job , a regular job .
It 's not that simple .
Well , you should think about it .
( SCREAMS )
Ben ! What happened ?
Just leave me alone . Please , just leave me alone !
Angie , get out of here ! Now !
What is happening to you , Ben ?
Pull yourself together .
( TAPS )
( BIRD FLUTTERS )
( EX CLAIMS IN PAIN )
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( PEOPLE SCREAMING )
( BEN SCREAMING )
Help !
Oh , my God ! Oh , my God ! Oh , my ...
No !
( GRUNTING )
" Gary Lewis . "
( PANTING )
( EX CLAIMS IN PAIN )
Esseker .
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
Hello ?
Where are you ?
I want to help you , but I need to know where you are !
Damn it !
( WOMAN CONTINUES SCREAMING )
I 'm coming !
( SCREAMING STOPS )
Anybody here ?
Is anybody in here ?
Fuck this place .
( WOMAN SCREAMING )
( WOMAN CRYING )
( SCREAMING )
MICHAEL : Mom ! Mom ! Mom !
- Mom ! Mom ! - AMY : Michael ?
Are you okay ? What 's happening ?
Michael . What 's the matter , sweetie ?
- There 's a lady screaming . - Where ?
- There , in the mirror . - In the mirror ?
I don 't see anybody but you and I in the mirror .
- You just had a nightmare , sweetie . - Okay .
Sometimes they can feel really real , but they 're not , all right ?
- Okay . - Okay , let 's go back to sleep .
Come on . In you go .
I 'm right around the corner , all right ?
- Love you . - I love you , too , sweetie .
DAISY : Can you leave the door open ? AMY : Sure , sweetheart .
- But you go back to sleep , okay ? - DAISY : All right , Mom .
WOMAN ON TV : ... not clear how it happened .
The 42-year-old is expected to go on trial this month for allegedly
sexually assaulting a former co-worker in her apartment
for 13 hours on Halloween night in 2005 .
Braunstein 's lawyer says his client was mentally ill at the time .
The Feds say they 'll seek the death penalty against a former mob boss
accused of ordering a hit on a rival .
The trial of Vincent " Vinny Gorgeous " ...
( ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )
BEN : I swear to you , I could feel my flesh burning .
I couldn 't breathe . It was like my lungs were full of smoke .
It was like a nightmare , but I was awake . I know I was awake .
- You think I 'm crazy , don 't you ? - I don 't know what to think .
I think you 're just going through a hard time in your life .
You 're under a lot of stress .
You 've been having those nightmares since the shooting .
- You know it wasn 't your fault . - They 're everywhere .
- What are you talking about ? - The fucking mirrors , they are everywhere ,
in the department store , on the corner of every street ,
in the window of every building in this city .
I feel ...
I feel like I 'm not the one looking into the mirrors
but they 're looking back at me .
There 's no one looking back at you through the mirrors .
You 're obviously ... You 're still conflicted about what happened .
Maybe you need to talk to someone .
A professional , someone ...
Mirrors are just glass and silver , Ben . That 's it .
There 's nothing behind them .
Will you please go get some sleep , okay ?
I love you .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Coming !
Hold on !
- Mr. Carson ? - Yeah .
You want to sign here , please ?
- You have a good day , sir . - Thanks .
Holy shit .
Lorenzo , I need to talk to you .
I just had the craziest day here . Your ex-colleagues came to pay us a visit .
What are you talking about ?
Well , you know Gary , the guy who was working here before you ?
Yeah .
Cops found him dead in a subway station in Harlem .
I never liked him too much , but , poor guy , he didn 't deserve to go like that .
Did they happen to tell you the cause of death ?
- What ? - Did they tell you how he died ?
No , no , they wouldn 't tell me .
Mrs. Sapelli is waiting for me at home . I got to go .
By the way , about that leak in the basement .
They 're sending someone over to work on that , beginning of next week .
AMY : We have a white male , 50 years of age , name unknown .
Following the completion of the external examination ,
the body was washed and lightly dried .
A Y-incision was made from the bilateral clavicular joints
to the xiphoid process .
- The tissue was waterlogged ... - WOMAN : Amy .
Yes , what is it ?
There 's someone in the lobby for you . It sounds urgent .
Ben .
What 's happening ? What are you doing here ?
Thanks for seeing me . Look , I need to ask you a favor .
- I 'm in the middle of work . - I know . Twenty minutes .
Yesterday morning you picked up a body .
Gary Lewis . I just need to take a look at him .
- Who is he ? - He was a night watchman
at the Mayflower . I replaced him .
How do you have his driver 's license ?
I found his wallet in the department store . Look , I just need to know how he died .
Why do you need to know how he died ?
Ben , you 've been suspended . You 're not supposed to be doing any investigations .
Amy , please , just listen to me . This is serious .
There are some very strange things happening over at the Mayflower .
I can 't explain , but it 's ...
This guy Gary Lewis sent me a package right before he died .
Thing is , I never met him before .
Inside the package were all these articles on the Mayflower , on the fire .
It was like he was trying to tell me something or warn me about something .
I need to figure this out . Please .
Gary Lewis , Gary Lewis . There he is , B-16 .
He slashed his throat .
There you go , there 's your answer . Your man committed suicide .
And you get a lot of suicide cases with people that slash their own throats ?
I didn 't think so . Excuse me .
All I know is , the police are still investigating this one .
That 's why we still have the body .
What did he use to cut his throat ?
A piece of mirror .
He probably broke the mirror into pieces
so he 'd have something to cut himself with .
( LAUGHING ) Seven years bad luck .
Esseker .
Are you okay , Ben ?
I 'm fine .
I 'm sorry , excuse me .
I need to see his file .
- What ? - I need his file .
- Ben . - What 's the problem ?
I just need to see his file .
Calm down . You 're not even supposed to be down here ,
and now you want to look at somebody 's file ?
Look , I 'll be off then .
Amy , you know where to find me if you need me .
Yeah . Thanks , Peter . I appreciate it .
- I want you to leave now . I 'm serious , Ben . - Amy , I 'm sorry .
I can 't leave here until I see that file .
It 's important , please .
Please .
( PAGES FLIPPING )
Amy , come here and look at this picture .
Look at the piece of mirror that Gary Lewis is holding .
And look at it up here in its reflected image in the other mirror .
It 's full of blood .
Yet in reality , it 's perfectly clean . Not a single drop , not a single drop on it .
So what ? It 's probably the angle from which the photograph was taken .
What are you trying to prove ?
What if the mirrors are showing us something that 's not really happening ?
- What are you talking about ? - No , just listen to me .
What if the mirrors are reflecting something that 's beyond our reality ?
What if the mirrors can actually make us do things that we don 't want to do ?
Like making Gary Lewis slit his own throat .
Ben , listen to yourself . You can 't talk like that around here .
Don 't you want to get reinstated ?
Amy , I 'm seeing things in the mirrors at work , bad things ,
to the point where I can feel what they 're showing me .
Ben , you 're driving me fucking crazy ! I don 't have time for this .
What 's wrong with you ?
Do you think I 'm making this up ? Do you think I 'm fucking lying ?
What medication are you taking to stop drinking ?
( BEN SCOFFING )
That 's a strong drug .
It has a lot of serious side effects . How many pills are you taking a day ?
I 'm sorry that I bothered you .
You 're right .
Thanks for trying to help .
( WATER RUNNING )
( HUMMING )
( EXHALES )
( GRUNTING )
( GASPING )
( SCREAMING )
( CAMERA CLICKING )
WOMAN : night at this bar . It 's a couple of blocks from here .
- LARRY : All right . Where 's the body ? - OFFICER : Calm down .
WOMAN : I can 't . How am I gonna calm down ?
OFFICER : Let the detective by . Step over here .
And there 's a guy been living with her at her place . There 's a guy .
OFFICER : All right . You say she works at this bar ? At night ?
WOMAN : Yeah , she works nights . She goes nights .
She comes home late . I don 't see her come home .
She probably closes the bar , right ?
Yeah . ' Cause she sleeps during the day , like early morning hours .
OFFICER : All right .
( GASPS )
( INTERPRETING ) I saw blood falling from the ceiling . Then she call me .
I want you to ask her , did she hear any noises , any sounds ?
BEN : What 's going on ? DETECTIVE : One second .
It 's all right , I live in apartment eight . I used to be a cop .
- Just tell me what 's going on . - DETECTIVE : Just a second .
I want to talk to the lead detective ! Angela !
- Who is the lead detective ? - Ben .
Larry , what the hell are you doing here ?
- Larry , just tell me what 's going on . - Ben , it 's not good .
Where 's Angie ?
Where the fuck is my sister ? Tell them to let go of me !
- I can 't do that , Ben ! - God damn it !
( BEN SOBBING )
( RETCHING )
( COUGHING )
LARRY : The water has obliterated most of the marks .
No sign of struggle or forced entry .
And the front door was locked , which means that
the person who did this either had keys to the apartment
or it was someone that she knew .
He would 've never laid a finger on her .
You know , when their father died , Ben took care of Angela .
( SOBBING ) She meant the world to him .
Listen , so far , his statement is pretty consistent with the facts , you know ?
We checked it out . He showed up to work at 7 : 00 p.m.
And the downstairs neighbors said
they began to notice the water leakage at around 10 : 00 .
The only strange thing , and this could just be a coincidence ,
is that Ben told the daytime security guard , Lorenzo Sapelli ,
that he was planning on quitting the job .
Like he was moving away someplace . He mention anything like that to you ?
No .
Lately , communication hasn 't been our strong point .
What are you gonna do with him ?
I figure we 'll let him go . We got no reason to keep him here .
AMY : Larry .
( AMY SIGHS )
I 'm so sorry .
Ben ?
Why don 't you come home and spend some days with the kids ?
I can 't .
I don 't want to put our children in danger .
She asked me to quit , but I wouldn 't .
- They came after her . - What are you talking about ?
I 've got some things I need to take care of .
- Wait , Ben . Please . - Amy . Amy , let me go .
I don 't want you to get in any more trouble .
- Please stay out of it . - I know who did this .
Well , in that case , you 've got to tell Larry everything .
He 'll never believe me .
Neither will you .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( BEN GRUNTING )
( BANGING )
( SCREAMING )
( GUN CLICKING )
( CRYING )
What do you want ?
Please , just tell me .
What do you want from me ?
( SCREAMING ) What do you want from me ?
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( GLASS CRACKING )
" Esseker . "
Hey . I need you to run a name for me . Esseker .
Echo , Sierra , Sierra , Echo , Kilo , Echo , Romeo .
- LARRY ON PHONE : Did you check online ? - I 've already done that .
Nothing . IRS and DMV .
- Where ? - Try New York .
- When ? - Last five or six years .
Okay , Ben .
Thanks . Get back to me as soon as you can .
" Mayflower burns , 48 presumed dead . "
" Berry confesses to deadly Mayflower fire . "
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
" Watchman arrested . "
" Woman , three children murdered . " Come on , Ben , connect the dots .
" Mr. Berry maintains that the mirrors in the store are the ones
" that brutally killed his wife and three children . "
" Mirrors are guilty . Mirrors are guilty . "
( PHONE RINGING )
- Yeah . What did you get ? - LARRY : Hey .
Look , I didn 't find anything under that name .
Shit ! Shit .
Do you want me to look outside New York ?
No . Hold on . Hold on .
I want you to run another name for me . Berry , Terrence Berry .
Terrence Berry .
Wait one sec .
- I think I got him . You still there ? - Yeah .
- Your guy murdered his whole family . - I already know that .
He 's dead .
( SIGHING ) Damn it .
Can you tell me where he was committed before he died ?
DR. MORRIS : You know , Mr. Carson , when one starts to perceive one 's own reflection
as a completely separate being ,
one is suddenly confronted with two entirely separate egos ,
two entirely separate worlds that can surface at any given moment .
A feeling of self-hatred , usually triggered by a psychological shock
can split the personality in two .
Hence creating two or more personalities with distinct memories
and distinct behavior patterns within the same individual .
The patient then has the false perception of the existence
of two distinct worlds , the real world and the world inside a mirror .
These recordings were used in Terrence 's trial .
You 'll see they speak for themselves .
DOCTOR : Why did you set the department store on fire ?
In order to destroy the mirrors .
Only fire can destroy mirrors , isn 't that right , Doctor ?
DOCTOR : What made you think you absolutely
had to destroy those mirrors , Terrence ?
They killed my Helen and my three children .
DOCTOR : For what reason ?
Why would mirrors want to kill your family ?
- Because I didn 't ... - DOCTOR : Didn 't do what ?
They asked me to find Esseker .
Oh , my God .
We all are looking for Esseker .
Amy .
Excuse me , I have to go .
DOCTOR : Tell me about Esseker , Terrence . Who is Esseker ?
I don 't know who Esseker is !
I don 't know .
ROSA : Mrs. Carson ? It 's Rosa .
( WHISPERING ) Mr. Ben is here . He 's moving all of the furniture around .
- Hey . How was school today ? - Good .
Good . I 'll be right back .
Dad ...
BEN : Sweetheart , just give me a second . I gotta take care of a couple of things .
Daddy , what are you doing ?
Honey , don 't look scared . Everything 's fine .
I think it looks nicer like this . Don 't you ?
AMY : Rosa , what 's happening ?
Take the kids downstairs , right now . Right now .
What the hell are you doing ?
Amy , you 're gonna have to trust me . This is for your own protection .
Get out of the house , right now !
Hey , are you listening to me ? You are scaring the kids !
If you don 't leave immediately , I 'm calling the police ,
and I warn you , you will never see your kids again !
Amy , I am not crazy . These mirrors are dangerous .
At first I thought it was just the ones in the store , but after Angela was killed ,
I realized they can get at you anywhere .
I promise I will leave the house . Just let me cover these damn mirrors .
What 's wrong with you ?
I know what you 've been going through hasn 't been easy .
But guess what ? It hasn 't been easy for us , either !
Angela was a part of our lives , too , you know that ?
It 's not fair what you 're doing to us , Ben !
Michael ... He 's acting so strange now .
He always wants to be alone . He won 't talk to me . He 's having nightmares .
Ben , your behavior is rubbing off on him !
He is six years old . I have to protect him !
I want to show you something .
- Ben , let go of me ! - You don 't want to believe me ?
Fine , I 'll show you .
- What are you doing ? - I 'll show you !
Are you crazy ?
- Have you gone completely mad ? - Just wait , you 'll see .
- See what ? - You 'll see .
See what , Ben ? What am I supposed to see ?
It 's not happening .
Amy , I swear to you , at the Mayflower ...
I am not lying .
Ben . Let 's go back inside , okay ?
Put the gun away .
Listen to me , baby . I want to help you .
Tell the kids I 'm sorry .
AMY : Ben !
( AMY GASPING )
( CAR ENGINE STARTING )
( SCREAMS )
( TRUCK HONKING )
No !
( TIRES SCREECHING )
( TILE CLINKS )
( GRUNTING )
Jesus Christ .
( SCREAMING )
Larry , it 's me . I need your help again .
I 'm trying to locate the patient-employee manifest for St. Matthew 's Hospital .
LARRY ON PHONE : Where is it ?
Where was it ? They closed it down .
But it was in New York . It 's where the Mayflower used to be .
The Mayflower ? The department store ?
Do you have any idea where they would store records for a hospital
that 's been closed for over 50 years ?
No , I don 't . But I can send someone to city hall to check it out .
If it 's a public hospital , there 'd be a record of it . Tell me exactly what you need .
Same thing . I 'm looking for a patient or an employee with the name Esseker .
All right , I 'm on it . Give me a couple hours , and , Ben , keep your head down .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( CAR DOOR OPENING )
Hey .
- Did you get it ? - Yeah , I think so .
It 's Anna Esseker .
I didn 't really know what you wanted , so I got all the medical files .
This is perfect , Larry . This is perfect .
What happened ? Did you get in an accident ?
Anna Esseker 's file , did you have to go to city hall for it ?
No , I didn 't have to go anywhere .
All the files in that place were in storage with the cold-case evidence .
Why , because of the fire ?
No , it 's before the fire . It 's a totally different case .
Anna was a patient at St. Matthew 's .
She was in the psych ward run by a Dr. Kane .
Now get this , she was only 12 years old when she died .
What ?
When the nurses went on their rounds first thing in the morning , October 6 , 1952 ,
they discovered that all the patients had left their rooms during the night ,
and they 'd all gathered in the main hall .
Ben , they were all dead , including the girl .
Apparently , they killed each other . I mean , it was a slaughterhouse .
That 's when they closed the place down . Who knows what really happened ?
- What about the doctor ? Kane ? - Well , they arrested him .
They found him dead first day of the hearing .
He slashed his wrists with a piece of the cell mirror .
- Thanks for your help . - Good luck .
Damn it !
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
Jesus .
" October 6 , 1952 . "
" Anna Esseker is diagnosed with severe schizophrenia ,
" leading to withdrawal from reality , delusional and violent behavior . "
" Pennsylvania , August 1951 . "
They don 't match .
Anna Esseker was discharged from St. Matthew 's Hospital October 4 .
Two days before the massacre .
( GLASS CRACKS )
She 's alive , isn 't she ?
You almost done , sweetie ? Okay .
MICHAEL : Why is Daddy acting so scared ? It 's not normal .
He 's way older than me .
And I 'm not acting scared , but he is .
- Doesn 't make any sense . - Michael ? What are you doing ?
Nothing .
- Okay , well , we gotta get going , all right ? - Okay .
( GASPING )
( SHUDDERING )
( CELL PHONE RINGING )
- Amy ? Amy , what 's wrong ? - AMY : Ben .
You have to come to the house right now .
( SOBBING ) I 'm so scared .
- BEN : Amy , what 's wrong ? - I 'm so scared .
- Amy , just tell me what happened . - There 's something in the house .
- Something in the mirrors . - I 'm on my way .
God damn it !
( CAR HONKING )
Come on .
DAISY : Dad ? When are you coming back home ?
BEN : Really soon , sweetheart . Come here .
- I love you , Daddy . - BEN : I love you , too , sweetheart .
I gotta go .
I 'm afraid to stay here .
There 's gonna be windows and mirrors wherever you go .
Anything that causes a reflection right now is dangerous .
At least inside the house we 've covered everything .
It 's the safest place to be .
Amy , I 'm so sorry .
No . It 's not your fault . I should 've believed you .
Come here .
Ben , you do whatever it takes to end this .
- You hear me ? - I will .
I 'll be right back .
( CAR ENGINE STARTING )
( CROW CAWING )
( DOG BARKING )
BEN : Jesus .
BOY : Yes , sir ?
Excuse me . Is this the Esseker farm ?
- WOMAN : What is it , Jimmy ? - I don 't know , Ma .
- What can I do for you , sir ? - I 'm looking for Anna . Anna Esseker .
There 's a man looking for ... You said Anna ?
Yes , Anna Esseker .
An Anna Esseker , Ma .
Look , I 'm sorry to bother you . I must have the wrong place .
What is it you want with Anna Esseker ?
I 'm doing a research paper on schizophrenia .
I became familiar with Anna Esseker 's case .
I just wanted to ask her some questions .
Go tell Grandpa there 's a man here who 's asking about his sister .
BOY : Okay .
BEN : Thank you .
BOY : Grandpa ?
ROBERT : You know , up to this day ,
visions of Anna 's fits still haunt me at night .
I helped my father fix up this part of the basement especially for her .
Her fits were too violent .
My mother couldn 't take her screams anymore .
( ANNA SCREAMING )
We had every priest , doctor , healer , coming in from all over the county ,
but no one could help her .
So finally , a Dr. Kane from New York answered my parents ' cries for help .
He rejected the idea of demonic possession , said he didn 't believe in it .
He was convinced Anna suffered from a rare form of personality disorder
and mirrors could help her .
He wanted Anna under his care , at St. Matthew 's .
My parents were very poor ,
but he agreed to cover all the costs of the hospital .
Where did she go after the hospital ?
Don 't you know ?
She died there with all of Kane 's other patients .
Mr. Esseker , I read the file .
Anna left the hospital two days before the massacre .
Dr. Kane altered the documents so she could disappear .
Where did you get that document ?
I need you to tell me where she went after St. Matthew 's .
She came back and stayed with us for a while .
What do you mean for a while ? What happened ? Why did she leave ?
- I don 't want to talk about that . - Why did she leave ?
Because strange things started to happen in the house .
With Anna ?
No , no , not with Anna anymore . No , she was totally cured .
( WHISPERING ) Strange things started to happen with the mirrors , didn 't they ?
Mr. Esseker , I need to know where Anna is now . It 's a matter of life and death .
Do not make me threaten you .
We sent her somewhere where mirrors are forbidden .
- Where the mirrors couldn 't find her . - Where ? Where ?
St. Augustine 's Monastery , on the road to Reedfield .
( CHURCH BELL TOLLING )
SISTER : How can I help you ?
I 'm sorry to disturb you , Sister ,
but I 've come to speak with a member of your community . Anna Esseker .
Is she expecting you ?
No , not really .
If you 're not listed , I cannot help you , sir .
Can you at least tell her that I 've come from New York
to speak with her ?
I work with Dr. Kane from St. Matthew 's Hospital .
It 's very important , please .
( DOOR CLOSING )
ANNA : St. Matthew 's closed down in 1952 . Who are you ?
BEN : My name is Benjamin Carson .
I work as a night watchman on Sixth Avenue in New York City
in the building that used to be St. Matthew 's Hospital .
ANNA : What is it you want , Mr. Carson ?
BEN : My family is in danger ,
and what 's threatening them is asking for you .
I came all this way to ask you
why the mirrors that were left over from St. Matthew 's Hospital
are so desperate to find you .
Please , Miss Esseker .
If you don 't help me ,
I 'm gonna lose the most important thing to me in this world ,
and that 's my family .
Sit down , Mr. Carson .
The mirrors are merely windows on our world .
It is not the wish of the mirrors to find me
but of what is imprisoned inside them .
What is imprisoned inside them ?
At the time that I was at St. Matthew 's ,
( ANNA SCREAMING )
Dr. Kane 's therapy for personality disorders
consisted of locking the patient up in a mirrored room
for several days on end , forcing them to confront their own image .
Dr. Kane was wrong about his theory .
There is no cure for schizophrenia , Mr. Carson .
( ROARING )
It was something else .
And whatever it was , it left me and entered the mirrors .
( SCREAMING )
Since that day ,
it has been collecting the souls of the people it kills .
I 'm sorry ,
but if I agree to go with you and return back to that place ,
I will make it possible for the demon
to cross the threshold back into the real world .
Do you understand what that means for my family ?
You can 't do this . You need to come back with me .
I 'm going to pray for you and your family .
That 's all I can do right now , Mr. Carson . I 'm sorry .
God bless you .
Gary Lewis , Terrence Berry and many other men have died trying to find you .
And because they failed , their families died , too .
Two days ago my sister was murdered .
My family will be next if you don 't help me .
Please .
Please . Wait , wait .
This is my family .
This is my wife Amy
and my daughter Daisy and my son Michael .
They 're beautiful .
They 're innocent . They 've never hurt anybody .
Please .
Take the photo .
Just take the photo .
Look at them .
I 'm sorry .
( SHOUTING ) Who the hell do you think you are ?
They 're just kids !
( PHONE RINGING )
- Hello ? - BEN : Amy .
- Ben , where are you ? - At the monastery .
- Did you find her ? - Yes .
Yeah ? Did you talk to ...
- Amy ? - Michael ?
Michael ?
Ben , hold on , Michael 's gone .
- What do you mean ? - I don 't know .
I fell asleep with the kids on the bed and now I don 't know where he is .
Michael ?
Amy , what 's going on ? Is everything all right ?
Oh , fuck .
Amy , what 's going on ? Have you got Michael ?
Oh , my God .
Ben , there 's water everywhere .
You 've got to be careful of the water . It creates reflections .
Someone is in the house .
Someone scraped all the mirrors !
Amy , where is Michael ?
I don 't know . I don 't know where he is . I don 't see him anywhere .
Amy , listen to me , you 've gotta stay away from the water .
Get the kids and stay away from the water !
- Michael ? - Amy ?
Amy ? Shit !
( CHURCH BELL TOLLING )
Which room is she in ? Which one ?
My family is not dying tonight . You are coming with me .
AMY : Michael ?
( MUFFLED SCREAMING )
AMY 'S VOICE : Daisy ?
Daisy , come here .
Come here , Daisy .
DAISY : Mom ?
AMY 'S VOICE : Come here , sweetheart .
What are you doing in there ?
AMY 'S VOICE : Everything 's going to be all right .
( GASPING )
No !
( DAISY GRUNTING )
No ! No !
AMY : Daisy !
Come here ! Get down ! Get down , right now !
Get down , sweetie . Get down . Oh , my God , are you okay ?
Oh , my God ! Stay right there . Don 't move , baby ! Don 't move !
- Mom , why did you do that to me ? - It wasn 't me , sweetheart .
You know I would never hurt you . You know that .
Here . Hold this . Hold it tight .
Okay ?
Here , get down , sweetie . Let me see . Let me see .
Let me see , sweetie . It 's gonna be okay .
All right ? I know it hurts . Stay right there .
All right . Give me your hand . I need you to hold it really tight , okay ?
Just flat and tight , just like that . Okay .
Now , I need you to listen to me , okay , baby ?
- You have to be very brave . - Okay .
I need you to stay here no matter what happens .
No matter what you hear . Do not move from this closet until I come back .
- You understand me , right ? - Yes .
Okay . Okay .
Do not move . I love you .
Don 't move .
Michael ?
Where are you ?
Michael !
Michael , what are you doing ?
Don 't be scared , Mommy . He just wants to play with us .
Michael , I want you to drop that knife , right now .
Do you hear me ?
You know very well you 're not allowed to play with knives . Don 't you ?
Come on .
That 's a good boy .
Give me the knife , Michael .
Michael ! Michael !
Michael ?
( GASPS )
Michael !
Michael ?
Michael .
Why are you hiding from me , sweetheart ?
Michael ?
( EX CLAIMS IN PAIN )
( FOOTSTEPS PATTERING )
BEN : ( WHISPERING ) You okay ? Come on .
( SOULS MOANING )
( GLASS SCREECHES )
It 's waiting for me downstairs .
Bring me inside . From now on , I have to keep my eyes closed .
BEN : Step up . You 're in the room .
ANNA : Strap me in .
I spent the darkest days of my life in this room .
Are you sure there 's no other way ?
This is for your family , Mr. Carson .
For your family .
AMY : Michael ?
( MICHAEL HUMMING )
Michael ? Michael , look at me .
( CRYING ) Michael ! No , Michael !
No ! Give him back to me ! Give him back !
No !
No ! Get out !
Come on , Michael !
No !
Please . Please .
ANNA : You must go now .
BEN : Thank you .
AMY : No !
( AMY CRYING HYSTERICALLY )
Why ?
( CHANTING PRAYERS )
Give him back , please !
Give him back ! Give him back !
( CRYING ) Michael !
No ! No !
AMY : Michael ?
Oh , my baby !
( AMY CRYING )
Come on .
One , two , three
five , six ...
Thank God !
Thank you . I love you !
BEN : Anna ?
Anna ?
( SCREECHING )
( GROWLING )
( SCREAMING )
( GUN FIRING )
( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMING )
Come out , you bitch !
( BEN SCREAMING )
( SCREAMING )
( GASPING )
( BEN GRUNTING )
( GROWLING )
AMY : Oh , my God .
Oh , my baby .
( CRYING )
I love you both .
I love you , guys .
( GRAVEL MOVING )
( BEN GRUNTING )
( INAUDIBLE )
( SIRENS WAILING )
( FIRE TRUCK HONKING )
Subtitles by LeapinLar